<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Satyajit Puhan - TMDs</title>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://satyajitpuhan.github.io/tags/tmds/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://satyajitpuhan.github.io/"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2025-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://satyajitpuhan.github.io/tags/tmds/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Internal Structure of Light Mesons — Prof. C. R. Ji&#x27;s Group</title>
        <published>2025-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://satyajitpuhan.github.io/blog/seminar-crji-group-light-mesons-en/"/>
        <id>https://satyajitpuhan.github.io/blog/seminar-crji-group-light-mesons-en/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://satyajitpuhan.github.io/blog/seminar-crji-group-light-mesons-en/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talk Title:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Internal Structure of Light Mesons through Distribution Functions&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mode:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Zoom Meeting | &lt;strong&gt;Group:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Prof. C. R. Ji&#x27;s Research Group, NCSU, USA&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;external&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;crjiresearchgroup.wordpress.ncsu.edu&#x2F;group-meetings&#x2F;archives-satyajit-puhan&#x2F;&quot;&gt;View Talk →&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I discuss the internal structure of light mesons such as the pion, kaon, and rho using light-front models. The study focuses on valence quark-level Parton Distribution Functions (PDFs), Generalized Parton Distributions (GPDs), and Transverse Momentum Dependent distributions (TMDs). Additionally, I highlight the mechanical properties of the pion and explore how these distributions behave in a nuclear medium.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Internal structure of pion, kaon, and ρ meson — JINR Seminar</title>
        <published>2025-03-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-03-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://satyajitpuhan.github.io/blog/jinr-seminar-meson-structure-en/"/>
        <id>https://satyajitpuhan.github.io/blog/jinr-seminar-meson-structure-en/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://satyajitpuhan.github.io/blog/jinr-seminar-meson-structure-en/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talk Title:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Internal structure of pion, kaon, and ρ meson in light front dynamics&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mode:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Zoom Meeting | &lt;strong&gt;Place:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; JINR, Dubna, Moscow&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;external&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.jinr.ru&#x2F;posts&#x2F;214775&#x2F;&quot;&gt;View Talk →&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk focuses on studying the internal structure of pion, kaon, and ρ mesons within light-front models. We systematically explore transverse momentum-dependent parton distributions (TMDs), generalised parton distributions (GPDs), form factors (FFs), and parton distribution functions (PDFs) for these particles.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the mechanical properties of the pion and kaon are investigated by calculating pressure and shear distributions through GPDs. The charge radii of these particles are predicted as well, providing insight into their spatial structure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To further understand the behaviour of the pion and kaon in nuclear environments, these distributions are studied in medium using the chiral SU(3) quark mean field model. The PDFs are evolved to higher Q² scales to facilitate comparison with experimental data.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The upcoming &lt;strong&gt;Electron-Ion Collider&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;NICA&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; will serve as crucial platforms to test and refine these theoretical predictions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Pion and Kaon Structure at HHIQCD 2024 — Kyoto University</title>
        <published>2024-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://satyajitpuhan.github.io/blog/hhiqcd-2024-pion-kaon-structure-en/"/>
        <id>https://satyajitpuhan.github.io/blog/hhiqcd-2024-pion-kaon-structure-en/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://satyajitpuhan.github.io/blog/hhiqcd-2024-pion-kaon-structure-en/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talk Title:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Structural analysis of Pion and Kaon with distribution functions&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mode:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; In person at HHIQCD, Kyoto University, Japan&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;external&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;indico.yukawa.kyoto-u.ac.jp&#x2F;event&#x2F;27&#x2F;&quot;&gt;View Talk →&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pion and kaon are one of the simplest meson structures to study the distribution function. In this work, we have calculated the time reversal quark transverse momentum-dependent parton distribution functions (TMDs) in the light-front based holographic model (LFHM) and quark model (LFQM) up to twist-4.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have presented the three dimensional structure of T-even TMDs for both the particles in both models. The transverse structure have been discussed with the help of two dimensional contour plot distribution in momentum space and average quark momenta in both the models. The T-even TMDs have also been compared for both the models and evolved to higher Q² to compare with available TMDs extraction data for the case of pion.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The collinear parton distribution functions (PDFs) have also been investigated. The unpolarized f₁(x) PDF have been evolved through DGLAP evolution from Q² = 1 GeV² to 16 GeV² and found significant behavior with experimental results. The spatial structure have also been studied through leading twist GPDs and have been implicated to understand the form factors (FFs).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Pion Structure at ICTS-TIFR 2024 — Bengaluru</title>
        <published>2024-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://satyajitpuhan.github.io/blog/icts-tifr-2024-pion-structure-en/"/>
        <id>https://satyajitpuhan.github.io/blog/icts-tifr-2024-pion-structure-en/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://satyajitpuhan.github.io/blog/icts-tifr-2024-pion-structure-en/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talk Title:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Structural analysis of pion with distribution functions (TMDs, GPDs and GDAs)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mode:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; In person at ICTS, Bengaluru, India&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;external&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=R3M5XIhKjFQ&quot;&gt;Watch the Talk on YouTube →&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-this-talk&quot;&gt;About This Talk&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I presented my research on identifying the internal structure of the pion using three complementary types of distribution functions: Transverse Momentum Dependent distributions (TMDs), Generalized Parton Distributions (GPDs), and Generalized Distribution Amplitudes (GDAs).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk was part of the program at the &lt;strong&gt;International Centre for Theoretical Sciences (ICTS-TIFR)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, Bengaluru, India.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
